You go first. Left side.
And Jared.
And Caleb. Yes.
There's something back there to kick
your butt. I know it.
It bites.
It'll attack.
>> walk up here again without looking back
there. Yeah.
All right.
Caleb, have a seat there. Sure.
How's everybody doing?
Not as good as we are.
>> [laughter]
>> I just want to say uh first, I mean,
thank you to my Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ for allowing me to be here. Um
but really want to give a a big shout
out and appreciation to my parents,
Gary Downs, Tonya Downs, and then my
sister that came along today,
um took off a little bit from medical
school, Cameron Downs. So, thank you
guys for being here.
Uh can we give them a round of applause?
>> [applause]
>> All righty, Calvin. You want to kick it
off? Yeah.
Calvin Watkins, Dallas Morning News.
Caleb, Shady always talks about family
and how important it is to him and that
kind of thing. What does it mean to have
your family here, especially during the
draft process and obviously the end of
it? Yeah, it's a great feeling,
honestly. Um everybody's so welcoming
upstairs. You can tell everybody has a a
real family feel around here. Um and
it's awesome because when I came on my
30 visit, you get to meet everybody and
I asked, "How long have you been here?"
There was countless people have been
here 10 years, have been here 13 years,
have been here 15 years. So, uh you can
tell it's a real family organization by
the time that people have spent
together. Shady, when you were doing the
the process with him, I don't I don't
know if you talked to him at the combine
yourself, but did you get that feel from
him that hey, this is the right kind of
guy we want? Oh, absolutely. I think I
talked about it last night, you know,
Calvin when he came in on his top 30
visit, it was
it the other guys that were there on the
visit were drawn to him. They followed
him and you can't spend more than a few
minutes with him to know that
[clears throat] that's just who he is.
And then you meet his parents, you spend
time with them and his sister and
obviously his brother. Um it was very
apparent and it was immediate.
Clarence Hill, DLS Cowboys. And
congratulations to Caleb. Uh
the Cowboys have made no secret they
wanted you from way back when. And can
you talk about when you had that feeling
that this would be a perfect place for
you? Yeah, I mean,
honestly,
I always said as a kid it's somewhere
with no income tax. So, this made that
list. Uh this made that list. Um and
when I took my um my formals, I knew it
was
The funny thing is we didn't actually
get a chance to do a formal even though
um we were scheduled for one. Uh
scheduling mishap happened. Uh so, I got
a chance to meet Coach Ryan and uh
thought it a genuine connection there
and continued that pro day. Um and when
I came here my for my 30 visit, I had a
great feeling and vibe around him
meeting everybody. So, I would say yeah,
I knew there was a big interest and uh
felt it was a good opportunity for me.
Around here, the the buzzword is slot
slot slot. I don't know how much you
thought about playing the slot or how
that fits you since you were a safety.
But can you talk about your ability to
do it all, play back in safety as well
as playing the slot?
>> Yeah, I mean, I would say if you watch
my career, I've played a in a lot of
different positions. Um show a lot of
versatility in a different ways. So,
yeah, I feel confident in my abilities
to play wherever they need me to. Um if
that's nickel in the slot, then that's
what I'm going to do at a high level.
Caleb Thad Archer with the ESPN. Has
anybody brought up Darren Woodson's name
to you yet? Are you familiar with
[clears throat] the
who he is here in Cowboy history? Yeah,
I would say uh
not necessarily too much, but um
definitely looking forward to learning
more.
When when you got here and you had your
30, but when you came in again today,
did it feel like home?
Yeah, put on the boots. Once you put on
the boots, everything feels like home.
>> [laughter]
>> Caleb Shot of the Athletic, uh Caleb,
can you take us through that fan out
there? They said that they were hoping
you'd be the next Ed Reed. And then what
was your response to that? Yeah, I mean,
I'm going to just be me. I don't know uh
be Ed Reed. I'm going to just be Caleb
Downs. That's the best way to put it.
And have you
decided on what number you want to wear
and uh has that been finalized? Yeah,
we're uh we'll talk about it another
time.
How about [laughter] that? You might
have to negotiate a few things, you
know? We'll see.
We'll see.
Nick Harris, Fort Worth Star-Telegram.
Your interaction with Christian Parker
today specifically, knowing that you are
a Cowboy and how excited you are to play
for him. Yeah, super excited, honestly.
Um
I asked him first thing, "What Where's
the playbook at? Where's the playbook
at? When can I get it?" Uh just cuz I'm
about ball and that's what I'm looking
forward to doing. Uh so,
uh he uh he's been genuine since the
moment I met him and I was glad he got
to meet my parents and my sister today.
So,
looking forward to where that
relationship goes. And if you do get
placed in that nickel spot, you got to
be a physical player. Can you talk about
your physicality? Yeah, I mean,
you can watch my film. I've never shied
away from no bumps. So, no contact. So,
uh I feel like
that's that's part of my game that is
going to kind of continue to grow and
I'm looking forward to it.
Pat.
Hey Caleb Petrow, walk with
DallasCowboys.com.
At each level of football, particularly
going into a big program like Alabama
and then going to Ohio State, you've had
your own set of challenges. Can you talk
about the the challenge you're looking
most forward to attacking to be
excellent at the NFL level? Yeah, I
mean, I would just say learning the
game. I mean, there's a different game
between college and the NFL. There's a
different game between high school and
college. So, uh I feel like me learning
is always the biggest thing that I want
to do. Uh whether it's learning on the
field, learning off the field, um
learning about finances, whatever it is.
So, um I would just say learning the the
challenges. My question uh how are you
doing uh with your leg? Yeah. Hey, I've
been better, but I'll start in FI for
OTAs. All right. It's your show. He's a
fast healer. Yeah, he's a fast healer.
All right. I'm just checking.
Jake.
Jake Slater, NFL Network. Caleb, not
every player coming into the NFL has the
benefit of a father who's played in the
NFL and a brother. What was the
messaging from them and how did they
prepare you for this moment? Yeah, I
mean, I feel like the biggest thing is
just process. I mean, that's always how
we looked at it. Continuous improvement
every day is the word that we use uh as
our family, which is Kaizen. Uh so, just
find your process to get better every
day.
You posted a photo of blue bonnets.
>> [laughter]
>> If I would have known that
If I would have known that, I meant to
do that. Um yeah, I was actually came
out here, I want to say a week and a
half ago, um for
for something unrelated to this, but
uh the flowers were super beautiful and
I was like,
I might as well take a picture. So,
yeah.
They like manifesting in pictures around
here. So, that helped you. Yeah.
Stay flowing.
Scott.
>> Yes. Scott Dixon with the AP. Jerry, did
you tell Caleb how long you've been
here?
>> [laughter]
>> He got to hear enough stories that he
knew it's been a long time.
His family. But um but while I got my
stage, I can't tell you uh how impressed
I am. I had a good visit with his father
and
their background in coaching.
And uh his uh his grandfather's
background in the service and uh
I thought that was one of the greatest
stories is
grandpa always treats him pretty
military.
Treats him like that. He tells it much
better. Yeah. Yesterday when he got
drafted, his grandfather walked up and
gave him a big hug. First big hug like
that. But we had a good chance to share
stories of he's unique to have the kind
of background
combination of life skills as well as
football of people that have actually
experienced what he's going into.
And uh that's uh he's taken advantage of
that. You can tell from the way he's
played it. He's used that and used this
uh the things we're talking about here.
But uh
uh boy, I'll tell you you uh uh you when
you got somebody that actually knows
them. A lot of times you uh when I'm
talking to somebody that's coming in, I
said I say the thing that in talking
with uh players that uh
are through playing and I ask them,
"What would you What do you know now
that you'd like to have known when you
first came in?"
And they said, "I'd like to have known
it was more urgent than I gave it.
It's Super Bowl time. Starts the first
drill."
And said uh "Now that I've spent my time
and had my years here, I just wish I had
thought harder about how uh
how big time that first drill is, the
next drill, the next drill. It's it's
very intense from the time that you get
in."
He he
walks in knowing that. He's got some
great input from a lot of people and
it's pretty obvious by the way that you
look at how he's done with his career.
So, uh real pleasure to meet his family
and
they're very accomplished, but they're
serious about this.
Caleb, I'm assuming you're aware that
two of your former defensive mates at
the Ohio State University are now NFC
East rivals.
Um so, have you tried to talk yet? Can
we Yeah.
Uh it happened the moment I seen him.
After uh the moment I seen Stoney, I
said, "Yeah, you're comp now. Get away
[laughter] from Get away from me." But
that'll be uh for you to handle on the
offensive side of the ball.
>> You got it. Um yeah, I mean, it's a uh
it's a awesome feeling to know that they
both got picked and along with Carnell
and there'll be more Ohio State guys
that get picked, but looking forward to
playing against them.
Joe. Uh Joe with Dallas Morning News. I
saw that some of your high school
coaches called you a film junkie even
when you were a freshman in high school.
Where did your commitment to film kind
of come from and and how did that kind
of shape your just cognitive abilities
with football all the way through your
career? Yeah, I mean, I say it always,
I'm a I'm a big learner. So,
that's that's the way that you learn
football is just to be around it. So,
for me it's always trying to be in the
building, always trying to be
like a sponge to whatever is there. So,
just putting in the time, being able to
learn from the film, learn from what my
team is doing, learn from what the other
team is doing. I feel like that's a way
to get better. Ryan, how apparent was
his brain works ability
from his visit and Yeah,
it comes easy to him, it comes natural.
I think you know, you grow up in a
football family, you know, you've been
around it, you've been exposed to it.
But again, I think I said last night,
one of the things we're so excited about
is it's not just him being able to
process it, it's him being able to share
and really command or demand that the
guys around him are all in the same page
cuz that's what great communicating is
what leads to great defense and that's
the thing that you you see in his
personality, he does not have
a problem taking charge.
Garrett. Garrett Podell, CBS Sports.
Caleb, um Malik Nabers mentioned a story
last night that you were calling out all
of his routes in a college game when you
were a freshman at Alabama. What do you
remember from that matchup and what your
thoughts are seeing him in the NFL?
Yeah, really really explosive player.
They had a really loaded offense at the
time when we played them at Alabama,
when they were at LSU.
And I do I do [laughter] remember that
game. Their offense was very good, but
it was definitely predictable. So,
>> [laughter]
>> it was
it was a it was a good experience to
play against him. He's a good talent and
I look forward to seeing him this
season. And how are you able to
kind of be at that level calling other
teams' plays out that early in your
career and how fast do you expect to be
able to do that at the NFL level? Yeah,
I mean, I think it just goes back to
putting the time in. So,
putting the time in allows you to see
things not just in the in the classroom
or in the film room, but also in the
moment. So, that's the big thing is
being able to apply it.
Sydney.
Sydney Siko, DG10 Sports. First
question, do you happen to have a signal
away game, you know, circled on your
calendar? Yeah, I mean, I took my 30
visit here and to Washington and
the first thing my mom calls me. She was
like, "Yeah,
they both play the Colts." I was like,
"Oh, okay, cool." I was like, "That's
great." So, yeah, that's
we're looking forward to that. I know
you can learn a lot from your brother
because he also plays football, but what
about your sister? What have you learned
from her?
>> Yeah, I would say uh
trials, honestly. My sister she had two
ACL tears in high school and still found
a way to go play college soccer. So, I
feel like going through trials and
finding way to
overcome them
is something that I always took from her
and the strength that she showed through
that. Um and
even now the the dedication she has in
her medical school. I'll call her
>> [laughter]
>> I'll call her like 12 12:00 noon.
She won't respond.
She won't respond and she'll respond at
like 6:00 p.m. "Oh, I was studying 6
hours straight." And I know she's
serious, it's that she's that serious
every time.
Um and it was actually funny the other
day I called her and FaceTimed her. She
was like, "You're lucky I'm putting my
book down for you." So,
it's a
I mean, she's great and I feel like
everything that she's dedicated her life
to is a is inspiration to me.
Anybody else?
And good. You heard from any new
teammates?
Uh here, I know
Booker reached out to coach pretty quick
after this election like I think he was
there last night, but how many guys did
you hear from? Yeah, a couple D-linemen
couple DBs
speaking of Kobe Durant a little bit.
Um and uh
>> [laughter]
>> Dak Prescott, he he hit me up. I feel
like that was the the special one being
able to I've been watching him since
probably I was in middle school when he
was at Mississippi State. Way to make me
feel old, man. [laughter] Mississippi
State, so So, way to make a great first
impression with Dak.
Mississippi State, so
Competition.
Competition. So, yeah, I mean, just
excited to get to work.
Scholar.
Caleb, I don't know that there's a whole
lot of guys who have played six CFP
games. I just wonder
that volume of high-stakes games, how
does that help now get you ready for the
pros?
Yeah, I think uh playing against
high-level competition is what it's all
about. At the end of the day iron does
sharpen sharpen iron, so um just the
ability to know that I played in big
games and
I've competed at a high level and played
my best in those games is it's a
positive to know that I can do that at
any level.
All right, we'll take a photo here. You
guys want to
stand up.
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
All right, thank you.
>> [laughter]